# MEREDITH STRICKLAND

Fullstack Web Developer | 504-352-8366 | mere.strickland@gmail.com

#### O LINKS O

GitHub

LinkedIn

Technical Project Demos

**Portfolio** 

## o SKILLS o

**JavaScript** 

React

Ruby on Rails

Node.js

HTML5

CSS

Python

Adobe Illustrator Adobe

Photoshop

AutoCAD

#### PROFILE

Fullstack Web Developer with a passion for making people's lives easier through technology. With experience in JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, and a background in Architecture, I bring strong skills in collaboration, adaptability, and client relations. As a gay woman, I see the importance of inclusivity in the development of the tools and technologies that we all use. I truly believe that tech should be by everyone, for everyone.

#### ☐ TECHNICAL PROJECTS

## Rita - Slideshow | Demo

Prototype for an app that helps caregivers communicate with each other and keep track of appointments and medications

- Collaborated with team to design and build a prototype
- Managed the team from conception to presentation
- Winner of the "People's Choice Award" at LYLAS Labs: Women at Work Hackathon

## Trip List - Github | Demo

A website where users can add recommendations of things to do on upcoming or previous trips

- Designed and built front-end using React, Redux, HTML, CSS, and Semantic UI React
- Utilized JSON web tokens and local storage to store encrypted user information
- Designed and built back-end using Ruby on Rails

#### Blobbers - Github | Demo

An interactive JavaScript SPA where users gain points by grabbing blobs of similar color, or lose points by running into the falling rain

- Utilized P5.js to create user "sprites and visual elements
- Used vanilla JavaScript for all user functionality

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Writer/Proofreader at TrustForte Corporation, New York, NY November 2017 – Present

- Analyze documentation to write 15 educational and professional experience evaluations per week of clients' qualifications for IT positions
- Edit and write technical documents in support of candidates applying for U.S. H-1B visas

Designer and Office Manager at Andrew Franz Architect, New York, NY January 2016 – March 2017

- Collaborated with Associates and Project Managers on design schemes, material specifications, and drawings
- Designed graphics for the company website
- Coordinated designer meetings, arranged interior design orders, provided customer service to incoming clients

# Designer at Christoff:Finio Architect, New York, NY January 2013 – March 2015

- Served as a project manager, scheduling approvals and deadlines between consultants, contractors, and fabricators
- Supervised 10 construction and millwork installations, including carpeting, shelving and cabinetry, and plumbing
- Collaborated with principals researching the most appropriate design schemes for 5 different projects simultaneously
- Surveyed project sites and created floor plans in AutoCad

## EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development, Flatiron School, Brooklyn, NY December 2018 – June 2019

Visual Arts, Bennington College, Bennington, Vermont September 2007 – June 2011